

MINJOO CHO

Creative Interaction Technologist

◆ HAMBURG, 20097, GERMANY +49-174-6231773

o DETAILS o

Hamburg Area, Germany, Hamburg, 20097, Germany +49-174-6231773 m.cho@indeed-innovation.com

> DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH 1987-06-30 Seoul

> > NATIONALITY

South Korean

• LINKS •

LinkedIn

Personal Webpage

○ LANGUAGES ○

Korean

English

Japanese

Chinese

German

o SKILLS o

Prototyping (Processing, Arduino, Raspberry Pi)

Computer Vision (Unity 3D, Processing, Open CV, Python)

3D Modeling (Rhinoseros, Fusion 360, Solidworks)

Machine Learning

PROFILE

Minjoo Cho has graduated from M.S in Industrial Design from KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, South Korea) where she has received her B.S in Electrical Engineering. Through her studies, she participated in participated in various interactive projects: Calm Automaton(A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Display), Ratchair(Furniture That Learns to Move Itself). Prior to her graduate school, she was a project member of Samsung Creative Lab(C-Lab) for Touch Music project that aimed to provide multi-sensory music player for the deaf, followed by her project management experience in Samsung Galaxy Tablet series and Google Nexus 10 at Samsung Electronics for 3 years. Currently, she joined INDEED Innovation GmbH as a Creative Interaction Technologist. Her main interest resides in reaching and combining ideas from different fields including Design, Technology, and Art embraced with Humanity where she always believes in.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Creative Interaction Technologist at Indeed Innovation GmbH, Hamburg Area, Germany

May 2017 - Present

As a creative interaction technologist, I explore opportunities to introduce new interactive systems (or product) to clients or share experiences/opinions towards the future and technological advance to the public. My current AI Installation, How Will AI Change You, was exhibited at the House of Beautiful Business, Lisbon in 2017.

Creative Lab at Samsung Electronics, Suwon, South Korea

June 2013 - October 2014

A developer / program planner of an interdisciplinary project in Samsung Electronics. Designing sound visualisation tools for the deaf.

http://www.minjoolisacho.net/experience/c-lab.html

Production Manager at Samsung Electronics, Suwon, South Korea

January 2011 - December 2014

A product manager of Samsung Tablets throughout the whole product life cycle. Responsible for Nexus 10, a collaborative project with Google HQ Handled two Samsung tablet projects (GALAXY Note10.1, GALAXY Tab3 10.1)

INTERNSHIPS

Research Intern at ATR(Advanced Telecommunications Research Institute), Kyoto, Japan

October 2009 - February 2010

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction: Participated in the early development stage of a listener robot for verbal communication with human specialised for teleoperation environment.

Computer Language (C, C#, Java)

Web development basics (P5.js, html, css, node.js)

Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, After Effects)

3D Printing (Ultimaker)

Rendering (Keyshot 5)

∘ HOBBIES ∘

Hand Drawing & Caligraphy, Music (Violin, Ukulele, Song recording), Reading books (Aesthetics, Philosophy)

Research Intern at Toshiba, Tokyo, Japan

August 2009 - October 2009

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction Human-Robot Nonverbal Interaction: Development of a visualisation tool to display "Interest Rate" read the Robot as a response to the visual input from the user.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea

March 2015 - February 2017

Degree: Master of Science in Industrial Design

Majored in Industrial Design, <u>myDesignLAB</u>. My major research interest is in introducing interactive DIY tools to invite general users (without technological knowledge) to actively participate in the design process.

The graduation project, <u>Calm Automaton</u>, was a DIY toolkit for ambient displays and was demonstrated in CHI 2017 (Conference on Human Factors in Computing System).

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, South Korea

March 2006 - February 2011

Degree: Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

How Will AI Change You, Hamburg

November 2017 - November 2017

Today, we humans are standing on the verge of a major technological shift. Scientists, technologists, and others are developing deep learning machine intelligence, to boost our own intelligence, and help streamline processes; yet these developments could have uncontrollable consequences. Where this could draw us is up for discussion, therefore, the installation, How Will Al Change You, gives participants an opportunity to be "The Thinker", reflecting on personal and collective futures with intelligent machines.

Calm Automaton: A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays, Colorado

May 2017 - May 2017

Minjoo Cho and Daniel Saakes. 2017. Calm Automaton: A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays. In *Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI EA '17). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 393-396. DOI:

https://doi.org/10.1145/3027063.3052968

Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration., Anaheim

August 2016 - August 2016

Tetiana Parshakova, Minjoo Cho, Alvaro Cassinelli, and Daniel Saakes. 2016. Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration. In *ACM SIGGRAPH 2016 Emerging Technologies* (SIGGRAPH '16). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 19, 2 pages. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/2929464.2929473

Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation, Kwangju

September 2015 - September 2015

Cho, MJ., Lee, B, Min, J., Saakes, D.P. Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation In KSDS Fall Conference 2015.

Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring, Daejeon

April 2009 - April 2009

Seung-Hwan Choi, Duckhwan Kim, Joonwoo Kim, Minjoo Cho, "Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring", Computational Intelligence in Robotics and Automation (CIRA), 2009

III TALKS

Woman in Tech Hamburg : Design, Technology, Art - the Convergence of Adjacent Fields, Hamburg

February 2019 - February 2019

This women in tech meetup discusses how women are leading the charge at increasing innovation within their respective industries. Join our Disrupt meetup for women in tech community in Hamburg to learn more about how women are revolutionizing the technology sector and influencing the success of other women and motivating them to pursue career development, personal development, skill development and continuous learning opportunities.

TOPIC:

Putting the HER in "HERO": Why We Need More Women in Tech

FIRESIDE CHAT: Toast to the Art in Artificial Intelligence, Hamburg

September 2018 - September 2018

While institutions and associations are still struggling with digitalization and transformation, artists are using their work to focus social attention to current problems and develop a variety of solutions and new approaches. That's why we want to let the creatives have their say-in parallel with the scientific and economic discussion—away from any idyllization. With Roman Lipski, Christian "Mio" Loclair and Minjoo Cho, we will discuss which vacancy AI can fill and how it enriches the work of creatives.

 $Related\ articles: \underline{http://www.indeed-innovation.com/journal/design-technology-and-art-the-fertility-of-adjacent-fields}$

Panel Discussion: Mind the Progress, Hamburg

June 2018 - June 2018

"Mind the Progress" discusses the relationship between content and technology, creativity and digitisation. As one of the four panels, I share opinion about how does technological advance influence content and how does content impact technology.

http://www.mindtheprogress.de/speaker/

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Workshop Leader at ICISTS-KAIST, Daejeon, South Korea

August 2007 - August 2008

An organising committee member of ICISTS-KAIST, an international conference on interdisciplinary fields.

- A Program Chair of the workshop session "Human-Robot Symbiotic Society"
- Webpage : http://icists.org/

AWARDS

National Science & Technology Scholarship

March 2015 - February 2017

Full scholarship for graduate programme

National Science & Technology Scholarship June 2006 – March 2010 Full scholarship for undergraduate programme Lee Geon Hee, Samsung CEO Scholarship April 2004 – April 2005